Guide to the Phi Beta Kappa Records, 1845 - 1974
Phi Beta Kappa Records, 1845 - 1974
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
1000-128
2
4
On February 24, 1845 a vote was passed by the Connecticut Alpha of the Phi Beta Kappa Society, establishing its ninth chapter at Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT.
The majority of the collection is from the mid twentieth century and pertains to some aspect of financial records. The rest of the materials include membership rosters, the organization and chapter procedures, and by-laws.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Given by chapter secretaries in the 1950s and 1960s.
Historical Note
On February 24, 1845 a vote was passed by the Connecticut Alpha of the Phi Beta Kappa Society, establishing its ninth chapter at Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT.
Collection Overview
The majority of the collection is from the mid twentieth century and pertains to some aspect of financial records. The rest of the materials include membership rosters, the organization and chapter procedures, and by-laws.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Phi Beta Kappa.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Greek letter societies.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --History.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Students.; Phi Beta Kappa. Connecticut Gamma (Wesleyan University)
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Original Charter, Constitution of the Gamma of the Phi Beta Kappa (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, Connecticut Gamma of Phi Beta Kappa, last revised and adopted by the Chapter, April 18, 2006
  - Form of Initiation manuscript (Folder 2)
    Note: Handwritten copy and edited copy.
  - List of Members of the Connecticut Gamma of Phi Beta Kappa, 1845-1875 (Folder 3)
  - Protest of Prof. J. Johnston, President of the Society on Election of Members Under Art. 11th Contrary to Construction Ordered to be filed by the Society, October 1846 (Folder 4)
  - Report of Committee on Election of Members & Art. 11th, Accepted by Society August 4, 1847
  - Report of Committee on the Constitution, August 5, 1851
  - Report of Committee on the Constitution, July 19, 1864
  - Report of Committee on Constitution July 20, 1864
  - Constitution of the Connecticut Gamma of the Phi Beta Kappa
  - Constitution of the United Chapters of the Phi Beta Kappa Society
  - Minority report on Alteration of Constitution of the Gamma of the Phi Beta Kappa
  - Report of Committee on By Laws
  - List of students expressing interest in being elected into society
  - Third Triennial Session of the National Council, 1889 (Folder 5)
  - Blank Invitations to join Society
  - Connecticut Gamma of Phi Beta Kappa, Wesleyan University, Centennial Celebration, 1845-1945; Downey House, Nov. 16, 1945
  - A Greeting to New Members of Phi Beta Kappa
  - Phi Beta Kappa Catalogue of Alpha of Massachusetts Harvard University, 1891
  - Phi Beta Kappa catalogue of the Gamma of Connecticut, 1845- 1906 (2 copies) (Folder 6)
  - Manuscript photocopy of Origin & Progress of the Phi Beta Kappa Society (Folder 7)
    Note: Original in North College Vault as of 12/78. Photocopy sent to Archives.
  - David S. Luft evaluations and recommendations, Phi Beta Kappa Triennial of 1925 in New York City; The Story of the Convention booklet, missing members information (Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's financial records, 1860-1895 (incomplete) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cash account ledger book, 1909-1961 (Folder 2)
  - Cash account ledger book, 1961-1973 (Folder 3)
  - Farmers & Mechanics Savings Bank savings book, November 1942-January 1964 (Folder 4)
  - Farmers & Mechanics Savings Bank savings book, February 1964-April 1970
  - Farmers & Mechanics Savings Bank savings book, May 1970-July 1974
  - Internal Revenue Service Tax Forms (Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1946-1967 (Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1946-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa offered two $10 prizes for Latin each year to a student from Middletown High School and Woodrow Wilson High School, 1945-1957 (Folder 8)
  - United Chapters of Phi Beta Kappa miscellaneous finance documents (Folder 9)
  - Price List for Keys, Bars & Chain, 1974
  - Price List for Balclad and Insignia, 1974
  - Price List for Membership Plaque, 1967
  - Financial Records, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Financial Records, 1953 (Folder 3)
  - Financial Records, 1954 (Folder 4)
  - Financial Records, 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Financial Records, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Financial Records, 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Financial Records, 1958 (Folder 8)
  - Financial Records, 1959 (Folder 9)
  - Financial Records, 1960 (Folder 10)
  - Financial Records, 1961 (Folder 11)
  - Financial Records, 1962 (Folder 12)
  - Financial Records, 1963 (Folder 13)
  - Financial Records, 1964 (Folder 14)
  - Financial Records, 1965 (Folder 15)
  - Financial Records, 1966 (Folder 16)
  - Financial Records, 1967 (Folder 17)
  - Financial Records, 1968 (Folder 18)
  - Financial Records, 1969 (Folder 19)
  - Financial Records, 1970 (Folder 20)
  - Financial Records, 1971 (Folder 21)
  - Correspondence to Prof. Joseph Holdich, 1844-1846 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Records by Professors Lane and Johnston, 1845-1846 (Folder 2)
  - Honorary Membership Correspondence, 1925-1942 (Folder 3)
  - Paul A. Reynolds, Secretary, Connecticut Gamma Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Folder 4)
  - Carl Billman, Secretary Correspondence, 1954-1959 (Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous chapter correspondence, 1961-1968 (Folder 6)
  - Other local and national chapters' correspondence (Folder 7)